# Sahan Senarathna

Colombo, Western Province, Sri Lanka

sahan es@outlook.com

0763507534

linkedin.com/in/sahansenarathna

## Summary

Hi, I am Sahan Erandaka Senarathna. From Sri Lanka. By profession, I am a web developer and entrepreneur. Also, I am currently a student at CISCO Networking Academy - VTA Sri Lanka. To tell about my journey, I was interested in and passionate about IT from my school days. My journey officially began in 2020 after leaving school. I came on my way, Gathering knowledge and gaining experiences. Web development is my primary skill. Also, I am learning Networking, System Administration, and Cloud because I hope to continue my higher education in Information Security. I think it will be a good foundation for my journey.

## **Experience**



## Freelance Web Developer

Fiverr

Aug 2022 - Present (3 months +)



#### Web Developer

Wixze Technologies Mar 2022 - Present (8 months +)

## Assistant Manager - GPS Monitoring

**Araliya Group of Companies** Oct 2021 - Jan 2022 (4 months) **GPS** monitoring GPS device trobleshooting & maintain

#### **Education**

## **Vocational Training Authority - Sri Lanka**

National Certificate (NVQ I4), Computer Networking Jan 2022 - Mar 2023



### Cisco Networking Academy

Computer Systems, Networking and Cybersecurity Jan 2021 - Jan 2024

## **Minneriya National School**

G.C.E Ordinary level | G.C.E Advanced Level Technology Stream 2007 - 2020

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Certificate in Software Engineering WinSYS Networks (pvt) Ltd WIN/CO/20/1712
- Introduction to Cybersecurity Cisco
- Introduction to Packet Tracer Cisco
- Networking Essentials Cisco
- Endpoint Security Cisco
- Network Defense Cisco
- Cybersecurity Essentials Cisco
- Cyber Threat Management Cisco
- Introduction to IoT Cisco
- Microsoft Windows Server 2019 Hands-on Training Part I Udemy UC-75fbeb76-87f6-42fc-8132-40432acea916
- Microsoft Windows Server 2019 Hands-on Training Part II Udemy UC-387431ca-181f-44ff-af30-dbafe07fa814
- Networking Devices and Initial Configuration Cisco
- CCNA: Introduction to Networks Cisco
- CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials Cisco
- CCNA: Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation Cisco
- Network Security Cisco
- Introduction to Hardware and Operating Systems Coursera

#### P853QQGKVGLY

- Linux Basics and Shell Programming Udemy UC-b2ddd072-8365-42c0-84e8-3f6a9f52c540
- DevOps: Intro to Server Administration Pirple rtekmdixtb
- Python for Beginners University of Moratuwa 5t7O5mwj0A

## **Skills**

Cybersecurity • Computer Networking • Network Security • Computer Hardware • Windows Server • Active Directory • Linux Server • System Administration • Internet of Things (IoT) • Cloud Computing